<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>Alex Payne</title>
 <link href="http://al3x.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://al3x.net/"/>
 <updated>2012-04-03T21:46:08-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://al3x.net/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Alex Payne</name>
   <email>al3x@al3x.net</email>
 </author>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reasonable Defaults for Programmers</title>
   <link href="http://al3x.net/2012/04/03/Reasonable-Defaults.html"/>
   <updated>2012-04-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://al3x.net/2012/04/03/Reasonable-Defaults</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Reasonable Defaults for Programmers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s well known that all programmers hate all other programmer&amp;#8217;s code.&lt;br /&gt;
Given sufficient time, all programmers also eventually begin to hate&lt;br /&gt;
their own code. This is life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a particular attitude among haters of other people&amp;#8217;s code.&lt;br /&gt;
A programmer believes his or her standard of writing code is&lt;br /&gt;
best. They use unit tests or some new design pattern or whatever makes&lt;br /&gt;
them feel special or better than lesser programmers. They actively pick&lt;br /&gt;
out the flaws of the code written by others. To them, the world should&lt;br /&gt;
be defaulted to their standards, and when they find it is not, they&lt;br /&gt;
become assholes to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have spent some time wondering what causes this unreasonable default&lt;br /&gt;
behavior. Why, instead of working to improve ones self and ones team and&lt;br /&gt;
ones community, is it so often easier to merely point to flaws?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not the first to notice this phenomena by any means. The Buddha&amp;#8217;s&lt;br /&gt;
first discourse describes it in the first two Noble Truths:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Noble Truth of dukkha: There is a basic unsatisfactoriness&lt;br /&gt;
pervading all existence, in all forms of life. Some Westerners call this&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8220;suffering&amp;#8221; but it covers more surface area than that. All things are&lt;br /&gt;
constantly in motion. Constantly changing. Constantly causing friction.&lt;br /&gt;
Before we acknowledge the second truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second Noble Truth is the origin of dukkha: We are conditioned by&lt;br /&gt;
ignorance to seek out objects and experience that cause pleasure, to&lt;br /&gt;
dominate and control and manipulate our world and to avoid painful&lt;br /&gt;
situations. The objects of our attachment are transient things.&lt;br /&gt;
Eventually they will lose their luster and suffering will follow. We&lt;br /&gt;
delude ourselves into thinking we are singular beings, islands removed&lt;br /&gt;
from the rest of humanity, the rest of life. This delusion ignores the&lt;br /&gt;
truth that we are all merely part of a continuing universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is a way out of the woods, I would think. And it comes through&lt;br /&gt;
dispassion. Some have said it&amp;#8217;s as simple as &amp;#8220;give it five minutes.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third Noble Truth is the truth that the cessation of dukkha is&lt;br /&gt;
ultimately attainable. We can cease suffering. The Buddhists call this&lt;br /&gt;
nirodha, which is the unmaking of craving and attachment. We can attain&lt;br /&gt;
nirvana through dispassion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth Noble Truth is the cessation of dukkha. Through a gradual&lt;br /&gt;
path of self-improvement, described as the Eightfold Path, we can mind&lt;br /&gt;
the middle path between self-indulgence and self-mortification.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   <author>
     <name>Alex Payne</name>
     <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
   </author>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>eBook User Experience</title>
   <link href="http://al3x.net/2012/03/07/Ebooks.html"/>
   <updated>2012-03-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://al3x.net/2012/03/07/Ebooks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;eBook User Experience&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often say that if I become a millionaire, I am going to have a library filled with Kindles. Each one is going to have a single book on it. And I&amp;#8217;ll hire a librarian for this private library, too. Because books aren&amp;#8217;t meant to be merely read. They&amp;#8217;re meant to be admired. They&amp;#8217;re meant to show off to your friends and your enemies. They&amp;#8217;re meant to remind you, every day, how you would read that copy of &lt;em&gt;Plato&amp;#8217;s Republic&lt;/em&gt; featured prominently in your living room if it weren&amp;#8217;t featured so prominently in your living room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s what&amp;#8217;s missing from the Kindle. How does one subtly announce to the world they&amp;#8217;re reading &lt;em&gt;Infinite Jest&lt;/em&gt; for the fourth time? How do fellow readers-cum-passers-by judge perfect-strangers-cum-public-readers in a park or at the beach?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh but Kindle ownership is itself a statement of status you say? Bullshit. Kindles are cheap and if you want credit for pretending to read War and Peace, you have to earn it by lugging that thing everywhere for a summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much has been said about how a book distributes its weight in your hand. How it smells like victory when you buy it new, flip through it, and put it prominently on your living room bookcase. When I see a Kindle at someone&amp;#8217;s house, I don&amp;#8217;t think &amp;#8220;oh, he&amp;#8217;s pretending to be well read, too.&amp;#8221; I think, &amp;#8220;I bet that thing is full of romance novels and the Twighlight series.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#8217;s why I&amp;#8217;ve decided to add something to my plan as a millionaire. I&amp;#8217;m going to hire artists to paint the cover of each book on the back of each Kindle in my library. That way, people will know just how dedicated I am to this particular farce.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
   <author>
     <name>Alex Payne</name>
     <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
   </author>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Brett</title>
   <link href="http://al3x.net/2012/02/28/Brett.html"/>
   <updated>2012-02-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://al3x.net/2012/02/28/Brett</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Brett&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Get it done,&amp;#8221; he&amp;#8217;d snarl. He scared the shit out of new kids in the control room. We used to fuck with them. Tell them Brett got it in prison. College kids working in a small market TV station would believe anything. Sometimes the dumbest of them believed people lived in the satellites. But nobody would question what we said about Brett. They&amp;#8217;d just nod and let Brett be intimidating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He intimidated me at first, too. That scar. The case of &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TAB&lt;/span&gt; in the break room fridge. Who in the Hell drinks &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TAB&lt;/span&gt;? Psychos who&amp;#8217;ve been to prison, that&amp;#8217;s who. His body hung on a wiry frame. His brow always furrowed. His eyes could pierce through the dark control rooms. His voice. That raspy voice. That scar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Get it done.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He showed me how to do everything in the first segment and then he hovered over me as I fucked everything up in the second. This was live TV. He stood over me and let me fuck up, even as the director plead with him to step in and fix it. Everybody will fuck up in live TV. That was his first lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that lesson cascaded into a second: don&amp;#8217;t expect help. Cascaded into a third: move foward. And a fourth: to learn success, you must fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me it was the worst job I&amp;#8217;d ever done. To him it was just one of the 365 10 p.m. newscasts that year. The fifth lesson: be excellent, but nobody is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning I found a two-page-long list of things I&amp;#8217;d done wrong in my locker. He took the time to review my failure. I should have kept my hands on the board. I have should thought ahead a few steps. I should have listen to the director. I should have calmed down when things got bad and just fixed the problem and moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made mistakes after that day. Everybody did at some point. But I got better at recognizing why I made mistakes. This is important. This was the sixth lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the few short years I worked with Brett, I learned he wasn&amp;#8217;t so scary. Quite the opposite. He thought it was funny people thought he was intimidating, but he let people think what they wanted to think. After awhile those eyes didn&amp;#8217;t pierce anymore. He was working on an idea for a children&amp;#8217;s book. He talked about it all the time. His eyes would widen and you could just see into him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He exploded with joy at perfection, when done was gotten without incident. Fist would pump. He&amp;#8217;d whoop and holler. He&amp;#8217;d rub his hands together. Grin ear to ear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was told Brett had died, I was at work. New job. Hadn&amp;#8217;t been at the station in years. Hadn&amp;#8217;t spoken to Brett in since I left the station. Still, it was the kind of news that hit me too hard, too fast. I left the office for the afternoon. Made up some excuse. Spent some time walking. Walking and bawling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s hard to describe how one person could influence my professional career, in a field I&amp;#8217;m no longer working in, no less. But that was Brett. I think about him a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I knew him better, but I didn&amp;#8217;t. The path to perfection is littered with imperfection. Sometimes you just have to pay your respects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Everybody fucks up.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t expect help.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Move forward.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;To learn success, you must fail.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Be excellent, but nobody is perfect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
   <author>
     <name>Alex Payne</name>
     <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
   </author>
 </entry>
 
</feed>